# **Huang Zhihao**

- iasky@163.com 18982203382
- male/1981.12

## **Proficiency**

I have been writing code and experimenting with new software since 2002. Most recently the majority of code I have written has been in C and Bash, but I have experience in Python, PHP, SQL and C++. Proficient in File System and NAS protocol (such as CIFS, NFS etc).

## **Experience**

### **Huawei Technologies Co., Ltd**

#### Software Developer - July 2007 to June 2010

Participate in the development of NAS prototype system, is responsible for the implementation of the CIFS protocol, implements the MS-RPC and security authentication module, in-depth understanding and grasp the CIFS protocol.

Participate in the development of a distributed file system, to achieve the file based RAID, applied for related patents, in-depth understanding and grasp the file system and the distributed file system.

#### Team Leader - July 2010 to June 2012

Lead the NAS protocol (CIFS, NFS) team, responsible for the development and maintenance of NAS protocol of cluster NAS storage products, analysis of customer needs and problems, enhance team skills.

#### MDE/DE - July 2012 to December 2014

As a designer to lead a pre-research team of LTFS, based on LTFS specification, add cache and data deduplication and compression to extend LTFS specification, and apply for related patents.

As a module designer and those responsible for maintaining cluster NAS storage products, responsible for the examination and approval of NAS protocol related issues and customer needs analysis.

#### Maintenance SE - January 2015 to now

As a maintenance SE of NAS protocol for maintaining unified storage products, maintain unified storage products, solve customer problems.

### **Southwest Institute of Technical Physics**

#### Intern - May 2005 to June 2006

As an software engineer to develop OA system and internal web site. Master the project development process.

## **Education**

Signal and Information Processing, M.S. Fall 2004 - Summer 2007 Sichuan University, Chengdu

Telecommunication Engineering, B.S. Fall 2000 - Summer 2004 Sichuan University, Chengdu